[Music]
hi and welcome to this what's new
session for cross environment interc
company postings my name is Brian nilson
and I'm a program manager with the
business Central team and with me I have
my colleague uh my name is Jos Antonio
Garcia and I'm a developer in business
Central what we will uh do in this
session is take you through interc
company postings just a brief recap of
what it is and what we did in the last
release where we did a a few uh new
features then we'll see um a demo of the
new capability for doing inter company
across environments that will be Jose
who will be who will do that and he will
also take you through the setup that you
need uh to get it working and then uh he
also has a few tips and tricks so let's
uh let's look into into
company inter company is for when you're
doing interactions transactions between
group companies like you all belong to a
group of uh uh a
business and sometimes the subsidiary
sell to other subsidiaries or you buy
all from a a common production
environment um and you can use inter
company to do that um it sets up your
partners as interc company Partners it
has a feature where you uh do mapping of
dimensions and chart of accounts it can
support multicurrency they don't all
have to be the same currency they don't
all have to be the same dimensions and
they don't all have to be the same chart
of accounts so it's very flexible in in
the setups that that it supports it
works through sales and purchase
documents and it also works through uh
General journals but let's just take a
brief look at what we did in the
previous
release we made a a One-Stop shop for
the setup so it's easier to to see the
different parts we added some cues on
the fact box uh so you can see what's
may be missing in in your setup uh we
did some mapping side by side we did a
synchronization so you don't have to
handle files when you import uh an
interc company chart of accounts or the
dimensions uh we improve the navigations
going to and from the different in
andout boxes so it's easier at least in
the setup phase and in the
troubleshooting phase that helps a lot
we added the ability to do bank-to-bank
transactions in general journals you now
also have the comments in in the journal
transactions and in the document
transactions and lastly we made it
possible that even if you accepted an
intercom transaction you can go to that
document and still rejected um so we
made inter company a lot easier to work
with uh so let's just uh look at where
are we in terms of uh
features before we start with the new
parts so I have an inter company setup
in this business I have a holding
company or my parent company and I have
two subsidiaries and I've set I've set
them up uh as IC
Partners um and I have a few
parameters for each of them I specify
what they're called where they are um
what if they're using a currency code
and if I want to Auto accept
transactions coming from them and I can
also I just turn on the edit I can match
them with a customer and I can also
match them with with a vendor so I can
use the customer and vendor uh
capabilities we have in the
product and um for the bank to bank I
can also set up bank accounts for each
of the companies you need to have a
mapping to your chart of accounts so you
can import a common chart of accounts
and then you do mapping for that and
that is what we built last time we we
did it side by side for one is the
incoming part like when you receive
something where do you want to map it to
and one if you send something out for
like a a a set of accounts or one
account which IC child of account
account do you want to map it
to um so that you can have different
childart of accounts in in the companies
that you uh do inter company with the
same goes for Dimensions where we also
set up a side by side um mapping so it's
easier to to manage but that's basically
it in this company I have only set up
same environment they are in in the same
us environment that I have so for this
release we have also introduced the
capability to allow IC partners that
reside in a different environment and
Jose will first show you an example of
does it work um and after that he will
show how it's set up yeah thank you
Brian uh so here you can see basically
side by side uh two different companies
the one on the left is on let's say 10
and one and the one on the right is in
10 and two so they are completely
different they belong to different
business entities but in reality they
are just one big uh company um so let's
try it out uh before if you wanted to
work with inter company uh across
tenants or across environments you will
need to download some documents and move
those to avoid some manual errors that
could occur during that time we decided
to allow inter company to work across
companies so in this scenario I have
this customer uh link to this company B
but for me internally in company in
company a it's just another customer
let's say that I want to assign some
desks and I get H let's
say
yep right now I if I post this we will
be internally handling as a normal sales
invoice and at the end of the process we
will be sending this information to
Company B uh this part has been done
before uh through inter company however
now across environments we allow it to
work basically as an attraction for the
user they don't know that the uh
customer that they're interacting is in
a completely different tenant so now if
we go and refresh the company B we will
be able to see that in the inter company
inbox we will have a new
entry yeah so if we go scroll down here
we will have our cues and if we go into
the details we will have a purchase
document with a different information
and the quantity and then we can
accept as usual for anyone who is
familiar with inte company there hasn't
been that much of change the idea is
that we wanted to make it seamless for
anyone working with inter company to do
these transactions across environments
all the existing functionality for inter
company is Now supported cross
environment cross environment means that
it could be handled with two different
environments in one tenant or across
tenants but you need to do some setup
and we can jump into it right now I have
here in tenant 2 I have a new company
that I want to set up with
my uh company a in tenant one so what we
will need to do is go go into the inter
compan
setup in both companies and we just add
a new IC
partner there is a new action that will
help us to establish this setup and we
can basically do it both in parallel but
this information will need to be share
across uh businesses so if we uh well
one thing since this is a new company
you will need to give it a unique name I
see new for
example and then
we need to create in a reference to this
other company and
then
connect the connect will give us a
wizard we will need to accept the
conditions because uh our data might be
switch across GEOS and there are some
privacies that you will need to be aware
before moving
forward and the setup is analogously in
both parts first we will need to know
where do you want to reach out for that
information to make it easy we provided
your company information that you will
need to share with any other
intercompany partner that you want to
interact so for example we will copy
these four entries that we see up
here so you can see the inter Company ID
needs to be the same so I don't need to
paste it again and we will do the same
backwards
once we know uh where do we want to
reach out we will need to authenticate
in order to uh generate this information
you will need to have a Microsoft
entryid uh registration application I
will give more details later on uh but
yeah so now you can see I have uh fill
in all the different
fields and then with the before we move
forward we will do a test connection to
verify that these details were
correct
if everything goes well you will see
this message that allows you to move
forward and save this as a new interc
company
partner from this point onward it will
be what Brian mentioned uh you can
basically establish the currency we will
pick up the one that is used by default
by the other company in this case they
are using the same one so that's why you
don't see a difference and you can
attach it to a customer and vendor and
have the function existing functionality
for these two parts as a small test you
can also for example copy the bank
accounts that the interc company partner
allowed for usage across intercompany
and you will have them so up to
you um that's basically all for the
intercompany setup from this point
onward you will not know that you're
working with a intercompany partner in a
different tenant however there are a
couple of tips and tricks that I think
that will be beneficial for you guys to
know uh first of all is
uh the authentication details these
authentication details that you see at
the very bottom need to be created in
aure as a normal app registration there
is more information on how to do this in
our
documentation uh however you can at the
end of the process you will need to
create a new Microsoft entra application
where you will introduce the client ID
uh descriptive name and you enable it
and once you have enabled it you need to
assign it this permission set that is
cross environment API cross environment
into company this will allow you to
basically send and receive uh
Communications and allow other companies
to log into your system for working with
inter company uh due to some
security
um requirements we had to remove the
ability to insert this kind of new
interc company partners because you will
be able to reach out uh without uh
limits so by the default only admins
have that permission but if you want to
assign it to any user you just need to
go into the permission set and assign
it this permission set create and
modified interc company
Partners another tip that we discovered
during our testing is that in some
situations companies that are across
tenant and across environments might be
in two different regions and they don't
have the currencies uh enabled that will
allow them to communicate with them so
make sure that if you're talking with an
intercompany partner that is using a
different uh currency than you are make
sure that you have it on the list of
currencies locally also on a more
technical details uh these cross
environment Communications are handled
by job as you can see in the in the
partner for example on the left the one
that sended the transactions you will be
able to see in the logs that there was a
send notification and a cleanup
notification uh the sending information
will be will be done in the name of the
user that started the transaction while
from that point onwards the intercompany
partner that you created through the
Microsoft entra registration will handle
it and I think that that's basically uh
everything to get started uh going back
to you Brian yeah and maybe it's
important to note because you say you
need to create an app like the
registration app yes but you don't need
to be a developable for for that it's
basically just a record in the aure
portal and a few clicks following the
manual and and you're done yeah and and
just a small detail uh for those of you
that don't need to work across tenants
uh this uh registration app can be used
for all environments within one tenant
so it's true that in this scenario we
had to use two registration apps but
that's only because we are working in
two different tenants if you're working
in only one tenant one registration app
will allow you to use inter so I set up
one one app for my company yes and I can
use it for all my Partners exactly but I
still need to do the setup for each of
the partners exactly to identify them
but the good thing is that once you do
the setup for Microsoft entra that will
be enabled for all the companies on that
environment you don't need to do it per
company just it's once once per
environment yeah super thank you Jose so
uh with this we hope that you will use
inter company postings more than you
already are uh now that you have these
new capabilities to do inter company
cross environment thanks for joining
this
question